So, I'm going to call my main function,
islandCounter, and I'm taking in the matrix here.
Now, what I first want to account for is the none.
So, if my matrix is equal to
none or if it is equal to the empty matrix.
In this case, I just want to return zero right away.
Now, if this is not the case,
I'm just going to initialize my island's variable to zero which is the number of islands,
and I'm going to want to do two for loops to loop through this.
So, I want to know the number of rows and columns.
So, this is actually going to be vice versa here.
Okay. So, I'm going to write my for loop.
Now, when I get here, I want to check if the element is equal to one
and if it is, I'm going to
increment my island's count.
So, now what I need to do here is I need to
do the breadth-first search I was talking about before.
So, I'm just going to have a helper method to do that.
To collect FindPartsOfIsland.
So, I'm going to go ahead and define that down here.
So, the first thing I want to do is I want to initialize a q.
Why did you choose a q?
Since we're using a breadth-first search here,
I want to be able to use a q so when I add an element to the q,
I want to be able to get the first element that I added.
Yeah, that makes perfect sense.
And I actually need to import this method here.
This is from the questions framework.
And then the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to append my indexes here.
So, another location.
So, I'm going to append this to my q and
now, I'm just doing a breadth-first search as well. It's empty.
I'm going to keep searching for other things around so
the length of the q does not equal zero.
So, what I want to do here,
is I want to look at the elements around it.
So, we mentioned before that I needed to check if they are actually there.
So, I'm going to write a helper method to do that too.
Okay. So now that I'm checking if
this is empty, I want to do something with this element here,
but i'm also running out of space,
I'm just going to draw a little arrow over here.
And I just got this little section off
here that I'm going to be using to finish this method here.
So, what I want to do is I want to be able to get this element here from,
let me make sure to go up a little bit higher,
so I'll pop this element off the q.
Then I want to be able to access
these two variables so I'm just going to set them to a new one.
Okay. So now that I'm here,
I want to check if this element is equal to one,
and if it is, I want to set it to two as I mentioned before.
So, I'm going to use a helper method right here to check
if these elements that are next to it are actually next to it,
and then if they are, I'm going to add it to the q.
So, I'm going to call that. [inaudible] this here.
So, this method is going to be called,
appendIf and I'm passing in the q,
and I also need the row,
column and both of these coordinates here.
Okay. So, what I want to check here is if the x value is greater
than or equal to zero and
is less than the number of
columns and if y is greater than or equal to zero,
and if y is less than the number of rows.
And then if all these conditions hold true,
what I'm going to want to do is append.
This is the q.
We got columns there.
So, I'm going to want to append right here,
and just to make sure I'm appending it the right way,
so I access the first element, y is right here.
So that's how my helper method is going to work.
So, after I do all of that there,
so a method here, I'm running out of space right here.
So, all this information here is just basically,
I'm calling this method on all the elements around it.
So, I'm going to appendIf and so what I need to do is pass the q,
rows, columns and what I'm going to do is x plus one, y.
So, it's going to be the elements to the right of it,
and then this is going to be the element
below it so left and on top. That looks like it.
Well, that went pretty smoothly.
Yes it did. After going through all the necessary steps before coding the solution,
the actual coding is a lot easier than if
he were to have just jumped in and coded from the beginning.
The interviewee also made sure to let
the interviewer know what he was doing when he was coding.
But he didn't read out all this code as he was coding.
We often see interviewees just reading out their code as they code,
which can get annoying and does not really build understanding with the interviewer.
Yep. This interviewee focused more on
explaining the purpose of the code while he was writing.
By talking out loud you give your interviewer
the chance to jump in and help if your logic is wrong.
You also proved your interviewer that you're actually thinking through all of your code.
If you just write code you might be spitting out a memorized answer.